# **ALEXIS SAN JAVIER**

Lakeland, FL 33805 | Phone: 863-513-5577 | Email: alexissj16@knights.ucf.edu

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/alexissj</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/code-guy21</u> | Portfolio: <u>www.alexissj.com</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

**Full stack web developer** with a background in education and research. A dynamic, creative, and motivated problem solver who specializes in JavaScript. A graduate of The University of Central Florida with a Bachelor's in Computer Engineering and a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development interested in full-time roles.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS -

• Front End: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, jQuery • Databa

• Back End: Node, Express

• Database: MongoDB, MySQL

• Version Control: Git

### **PROJECTS**

**HomeBody** – Github: github.com/code-guy21/Homebody | Deployed: homebody-fitness.herokuapp.com Web application that auto generates user workouts based on exercise preferences

- Worked on a team of four and was responsible for building Authentication flow, API, and Database
- Tech Stack: React, Node, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, Passport, Cookie-Session

**Droplet** – Github: <u>github.com/code-guy21/droplet</u> | Deployed: <u>project-droplet.herokuapp.com</u> Social media web application that allows users to comment on and create text-based posts

- Led a team of four and was responsible for building API, Database, and Authentication flow
- Tech Stack: jQuery, HTML, CSS, Node, Express, MySQL, Sequelize

**ReactBooks** – Github: <u>github.com/code-guy21/ReactBooks</u> | Deployed: <u>reactbooksgo.herokuapp.com</u> Web application that implements Google Books API and allow users to search for and save book titles

- Worked independently to build Front End, Database, and API
- Tech Stack: React, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose

### **WORK**

### **EXPERIENCE**

**TRILOGY** – Remote

09/2020 – Present

# **Teaching Assistant & Tutor**

 Responsible for assisting instructional team and providing technical/educational support to students as part of a full stack web development program

**SYNAPSE** - Orlando, FL

11/2016 – 09/2018

#### **After School Coordinator**

• Founding employee responsible for developing program structure, lesson plans, and projects for a roster of ~30 students as part of an after-school STEM curriculum.

- Coordinated program execution and provided engaging and in-depth lecture to students, resulting in positive reviews and enrollment growth
- Successfully planned and executed a robotics challenge as part of <u>The Modern Classroom's</u> educational tour, which led them to become repeat clients and partners.

# THE UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL FLORIDA - Orlando, FL

01/2017 - 05/2018

# **Research Assistant**

- Collaborated with researchers and engineers to develop simulations, run experiments, and troubleshoot testing equipment to ensure consistent and accurate data collection.
- Successfully developed a virtual-reality brain simulation to test the memory and retention rates of medical students, using Unreal Engine and HTC Vive, as part of a study conducted by Dr. Grace Teo

#### **EDUCATION**

# <u>Certificate in Full Stack Web Development</u> – Orlando, FL

2020

The University of Central Florida

# Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering – Orlando, FL

2017

The University of Central Florida

# OTHER RELEVANT INFORMATION

**Volunteerism:** UNICEF at UCF – Vice President (2015) **Additional Languages:** Spanish (Bilingual Proficiency)

Awards: Dean's List—UCF (2015,2017), President's List—UCF (2012)